<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="ch05">
  <title>Native Libraries</title>
  <para>Many popular elliptic curve libraries are written in C, C++ and other languages. This chapter discusses how to test native libraries like BoringSSL, Botan, Crypto++ and OpenSSL.</para>
  <para>Each native library you want to test will need a shim library for use in the ECTester program. The shim library will depend on the native library, and have a name like <code>boringssl_provider.so</code>, <code>botan_provider.so</code>, <code>cryptopp_provider.so</code> and <code>openssl_provider.so</code>.</para>
  <para>There are fours steps to test a native library using ECTester. The first step is build the shim library. The second step is build <code>ECTesterStandalone.jar</code>. The third step is running the collection to collect data. The fourth step is plot the graphs to visualize the data.</para>
  <para>The steps below use Crypto++ as an example. You should use the appropriate library name when testing other libraries, such as BoringSSL, Botan, or OpenSSL.</para>
  <section>
    <title>Build environment</title>
    <para>There are two important environmental variables that should be set in your environment. First, you should set <code>JAVA_HOME</code>. The tooling uses <code>JAVA_HOME</code> to locate native Java library headers, like <code>jni.h</code>. Second, you should set <code>PKG_CONFIG_PATH</code>. The makefile uses <code>PKG_CONFIG_PATH</code> to locate a library's <code>*.pc</code> file.</para>
    <para>Linux distributions uses different paths for libraries. <code>PKG_CONFIG_PATH</code> attempts to abstract away the path differences but it needs help at times. On Debian and derivatives, like Ubuntu, the library path is <code>/lib</code> and <code>/usr/lib</code>. On Red Hat and derivatives, like Fedora, the library path is <code>/lib64</code> and <code>/usr/lib64</code> on 64-bit machines. You may need to tweak the makefile and other configuration files for distros like Fedora.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Build library shims</title>
    <para>There are two ways to build the shared libraries. First, from the ECTester and <code>jni/</code> directory, build the shim using the <code>Makefile</code>.</para>
    <programlisting>cd ECTester
cd src/cz/crcs/ectester/standalone/libs/jni
PKG_CONFIG_PATH=/usr/lib64/pkgconfig/ make cryptopp</programlisting>
    <para>Note the use of <code>make cryptopp</code> to build just the Crypto++ library. If all goes well then you should see output similar to the following.</para>
    <programlisting>g++ -I/usr/local/include  -fPIC -I"/usr/lib/jvm/java-1.8.0-o
penjdk-1.8.0.212.b04-0.fc30.x86_64/include" -I"/usr/lib/jvm/
java-1.8.0-openjdk-1.8.0.212.b04-0.fc30.x86_64/include/linux
" -I. -O2 -c cryptopp.cpp
g++ -fPIC -I"/usr/lib/jvm/java-1.8.0-openjdk-1.8.0.212.b04-0
.fc30.x86_64/include" -I"/usr/lib/jvm/java-1.8.0-openjdk-1.8
.0.212.b04-0.fc30.x86_64/include/linux" -I. -O2 -c cpp_utils
.cpp
cc -o lib_timing.so -shared -fPIC -I"/usr/lib/jvm/java-1.8.0
-openjdk-1.8.0.212.b04-0.fc30.x86_64/include" -I"/usr/lib/jv
m/java-1.8.0-openjdk-1.8.0.212.b04-0.fc30.x86_64/include/lin
ux" -I. -O2 -Wl,-soname,lib_timing.so c_timing.c
g++ -fPIC -shared -O2 -o cryptopp_provider.so -Wl,-rpath,/li
b cryptopp.o cpp_utils.o -L. -L/usr/local/lib -lcryptopp  -l
:lib_timing.so</programlisting>
    <tip>
      <para>Crypto++ is unique among packages because it has different names depending on the distro. On Debian and derivatives, like Ubuntu, the library name is <code>libcrypto++</code>, and the development package with header files is <code>crypto++-dev</code>. On Red Hat and derivatives, like Fedora, the library name is <code>cryptopp</code>, and the development package with header files is <code>cryptopp-devel</code>.</para>
      <para>If you need to change the library name then use <code>sed</code> on the file. For example, to change the library name in the makefile, run the command</para>
      <programlisting>sed -i 's/libcrypto++/libcryptopp/g' Makefile</programlisting>
    </tip>
    <para>Second, from the ECTester source code directory, use <code>ant</code> to build the source code.</para>
    <programlisting>cd ECTester
ant -f build-standalone.xml libs</programlisting>
    <para>This will compile the shared libraries which ECTester uses via the Java Native Interface to work with native libraries. That makefile uses <code>pkg-config</code> to find Crypto++, so all of that should apply.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Build ECTesterStandalone.jar</title>
    <para>Build <code>ECTesterStandalone.jar</code> with <code>ant -f build-standalone.xml jar</code>, possibly run this twice. If all goes well then the build should finish with the message <emphasis>BUILD SUCCESSFUL</emphasis>.</para>
    <programlisting>Buildfile: /home/test/ECTester/build-standalone.xml
-pre-init:
-init-private:
-init-user:
...

-do-jar-copylibs:
 [copylibs] Copy libraries to /home/test/ECTester/dist/lib.
 [copylibs] Building jar: /home/test/ECTester/dist/ECTesterS
tandalone.jar
     [echo] To run this application from the command line wi
thout Ant, try:
     [echo] java -jar "/home/test/ECTester/dist/ECTesterStan
dalone.jar"
...

jar:

BUILD SUCCESSFUL
Total time: 11 seconds</programlisting>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Run the collection</title>
    <para>Go to <code>dist/</code> and run the collection.</para>
    <programlisting>cd dist/
java -jar ECTesterStandalone.jar list-libs</programlisting>
    <para>It should list Crypto++ as available, together with other libraries that
ECTester was able to compile the shims for (they were available in the system)
and with pure Java libraries. If it doesn't list Crypto++, something went wrong
with the above steps.</para>
    <para>Then do something like the following.</para>
    <programlisting>java -jar ECTesterStandalone.jar ecdsa \
  -n 500000 -nc secg/sect233r1 \
  -o out.csv Crypto++</programlisting>
    <para>That should perform 500k signatures over the sect233r1 curve and output the data
into out.csv.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Plot the graphs</title>
    <para>Go to <code>util/</code>, run the <code>plot_dsa.ipynb</code> Jupyter notebook and follow the instructions there to plot the ECDSA data from out.csv.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
